{
  "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
  "name": "Tube and Tubing",
  "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the colour code that indicates the following types of copper tube. Type M:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "yellow",
        "blue",
        "green",
        "red"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["red"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the colour code that indicates the following types of copper tube. Type DWV: ",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "yellow",
          "blue",
          "green",
          "red"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["yellow"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the colour code that indicates the following types of copper tube. Type L: ",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "yellow",
          "blue",
          "green",
          "red"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["blue"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the colour code that indicates the following types of copper tube. Type K:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "yellow",
          "blue",
          "green",
          "red"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["green"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List three (3) advantages of copper tube over steel pipe.",
      "type": "checkbox_type",
      "options": [
        "Malleability",
        "Ductility",
        "Corrosion resistance"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Malleability",
        "Ductility",
        "Corrosion resistance"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the types of copper tube K, L and M, in order of their wall thickness (thickest first) and state the wall thickness for 1/2\" tube in each case. Type K wall thickness for 1/2 tube _________",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "0.049",
        "0.040",
        "0.028"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["0.049"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the types of copper tube K, L and M, in order of their wall thickness (thickest first) and state the wall thickness for 1/2\" tube in each case. Type L wall thickness for 1/2 tube _________",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "0.049",
          "0.040",
          "0.028"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["0.040"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the types of copper tube K, L and M, in order of their wall thickness (thickest first) and state the wall thickness for 1/2\" tube in each case. Type M wall thickness for 1/2 tube _________",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "0.049",
          "0.040",
          "0.028"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["0.028"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List three (3) applications of DWV copper tube in the piping trade.",
      "type": "checkbox_type",
      "options": [
        "Drains",
        "Wastes",
        "Vents"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Drains",
        "Wastes",
        "Vents"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List three (3) applications of Type K copper tube in the piping trades.",
      "type": "checkbox_type",
      "options": [
        "Water service lines - soft copper",
        "Water distribution systems",
        "Low-pressure steam lines"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Water service lines - soft copper",
        "Water distribution systems",
        "Low-pressure steam lines"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the application of Type L copper tube in the Gas industry:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Gas industry: only for above-ground systems",
          "Gas industry: for underground systems only",
          "Gas industry: for high-pressure systems",
          "Gas industry: for low-pressure systems only",
        "Gas industry: below-grade piping if factory coated, above-ground for all systems up to 1 1/4 NPS"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Gas industry: below-grade piping if factory coated, above-ground for all systems up to 1 1/4 NPS"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the application of Type L copper tube in the Plumbing:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Plumbing: only for water distribution",
          "Plumbing: for gas distribution",
          "Plumbing: DWV, water service, water distribution",
          "Plumbing: for electrical conduit",
          "Plumbing: for HVAC systems"
        
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Plumbing: DWV, water service, water distribution"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What is the main application of Type M copper tube?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Residential and light commercial in building water and heating lines",
        "Industrial applications with high pressure",
        "Gas distribution systems",
        "Electrical conduit for residential buildings",
        "Underground water service"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Residential and light commercial in building water and heating lines"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "In what ways does soft temper copper tube differ from hard temper copper tube?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Soft copper can be bent without the use of special bending tools",
        "Hard copper is more flexible",
        "Soft copper is used for high-pressure systems",
        "Hard copper is easier to cut",
        "Soft copper is more resistant to corrosion"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Soft copper can be bent without the use of special bending tools"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What is the greatest disadvantage of copper pipe over iron or steel pipe?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Lower strength",
        "Higher rate of expansion",
        "Higher cost",
        "Less corrosion resistance",
        "More difficult to join"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Higher rate of expansion"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "In what sizes is DWV tube manufactured?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "1/2'' through 4'', in straight lengths of 10' to 15'",
          "1'' through 5'', in straight lengths of 8' to 16'",
          "2'' through 8'', in straight lengths of 14' to 22'",
          "1 1/4'' through 6'', in straight lengths of 12' to 20'",
          "3/4'' through 7'', in straight lengths of 11' to 19'"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["1 1/4'' through 6'', in straight lengths of 12' to 20'"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What are the minimum sizes of tube made in the following types? Type M:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "1/4''",
        "1/6''",
        "1/4",
        "1/2''"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["1/4''"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What are the minimum sizes of tube made in the following types? Type K:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "1/4''",
          "1/6''",
          "1/4",
          "1/2''"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["1/4''"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What are the minimum sizes of tube made in the following types? Type L:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "1/4''",
          "1/6''",
          "1/4",
          "1/2''"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["1/4"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What are the minimum sizes of tube made in the following types? Type DWV:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "1/4''",
          "1/6''",
          "1 1/4''",
          "1/2''"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["1 1/4''"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What is the essential difference between oxygen tube and regular type K or L tube?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Oxygen tube is cleaned and capped",
        "Oxygen tube is thicker",
        "Oxygen tube is more flexible",
        "Oxygen tube is longer",
        "Oxygen tube is painted"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Oxygen tube is cleaned and capped"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "Copper pipe is made from 99.7% pure copper. Explain what 99.7% pure copper means.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "The copper is mixed with 0.3% other metals",
          "The copper is 100% pure",
          "The copper has 99.7% conductivity",
          "The copper has only 0.3% impurities",
          "The copper has 99.7% strength"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "The copper has only 0.3% impurities"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "Copper is used with other metals to form metallic alloys. Name one copper alloy and list the materials (and %) from which it is compounded.",
      "type": "checkbox_type",
      "options": [
        "Yellow Brass - 66% copper and 34% zinc",
        "Red Brass - 85% copper and 15% zinc",
        "Bronze - 90% copper and 10 % tin"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Yellow Brass - 66% copper and 34% zinc",
        "Red Brass - 85% copper and 15% zinc",
        "Bronze - 90% copper and 10 % tin"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the types of copper tube used for the following applications. Hot and cold water lines:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Types K, L, and M",
        "Types DWV, K, L, and M",
        "Types K and L",
        "Type K, soft; Type L, soft, factory coated; Type G, factory coated"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Types K, L, and M"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the types of copper tube used for the following applications. Drainage waste and vent lines:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Types K, L, and M",
          "Types DWV, K, L, and M",
          "Types K and L",
          "Type K, soft; Type L, soft, factory coated; Type G, factory coated"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Types DWV, K, L, and M"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the types of copper tube used for the following applications. Water heating system:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Types K, L, and M",
          "Types DWV, K, L, and M",
          "Types K and L",
          "Type K, soft; Type L, soft, factory coated; Type G, factory coated"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Types K, L, and M"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the types of copper tube used for the following applications. Steam heating systems:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Types K, L, and M",
          "Types DWV, K, L, and M",
          "Types K and L",
          "Type K, soft; Type L, soft, factory coated; Type G, factory coated"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Types K and L"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "List the types of copper tube used for the following applications. Underground gas lines:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Types K, L, and M",
          "Types DWV, K, L, and M",
          "Types K and L",
          "Type K, soft; Type L, soft, factory coated; Type G, factory coated"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Type K, soft; Type L, soft, factory coated; Type G, factory coated"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What does the abbreviation SPS mean when applied to copper pipe?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Special Pipe Size",
          "Standard Pressure System",
          "Single Pipe System",
          "Standard Pipe Size/Steel Pipe Size",
          "Seamless Pipe Standard"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Standard Pipe Size/Steel Pipe Size"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "Copper tube is lighter than the same size steel pipe, but copper is heavier than steel. Explain.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Copper tube is made with less material than steel pipe",
          "Copper tube is hollow, while steel pipe is solid",
          "Copper tube is used for different applications than steel pipe",
          "Copper tube is manufactured using a different process than steel pipe",
        "Copper tube has a thinner wall thickness than steel pipe, while copper has a greater relative density or specific gravity than steel"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Copper tube has a thinner wall thickness than steel pipe, while copper has a greater relative density or specific gravity than steel"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What is the coefficient of expansion for copper?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "0.00001234°C or 0.0000102°F",
        "0.00000897°C or 0.0000075°F",
        "0.00001122°C or 0.0000099°F",
        "0.00001071°C or 0.0000095°F",
        "0.00000984°C or 0.0000087°F"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["0.00001071°C or 0.0000095°F"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What is the chemical symbol for copper?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Cu",
        "Co",
        "C",
        "Cp",
        "Cm"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Cu"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "Copper pipe is measured by its approximate _______ up to _______ and by its actual _______ for _______ and over.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "outside diameter (OD), 10'' NPS, inside diameter (ID), 12''",
          "thickness, 8'' NPS, length, 10''",
          "inside diameter (ID), 6'' NPS, wall thickness, 8''",
          "length, 14'' NPS, diameter, 16''",
          "inside diameter (ID),  12'' NPS, outside diameter (OD), 14''"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["inside diameter (ID),  12'' NPS, outside diameter (OD), 14''"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "Copper tube is measured by its approximate _______.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "outside diameter (OD)",
          "wall thickness",
          "length",
          "inside diameter (ID) - NPS",
          "weight"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["inside diameter (ID) - NPS"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "Copper tubing is measured by its actual _______.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "inside diameter (ID) and length",
          "length and weight",
          "outside diameter (OD) and wall thickness",
          "thickness and flexibility",
          "inside diameter (ID) and pressure rating"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["outside diameter (OD) and wall thickness"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "Copper tube can be joined by the following methods:",
      "type": "checkbox_type",
      "options": [
        "Soldering",
        "Flared fittings",
        "Compression fittings",
        "Brazing",
        "Press connect"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Soldering",
        "Flared fittings",
        "Compression fittings",
        "Brazing",
        "Press connect"
      ],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "A Tylok fitting differs from a standard compression fitting. Explain the difference.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "Tylok has a larger diameter",
          "Tylok uses an additional ferrule",
          "Tylok is made of a different material",
          "Tylok requires a special tool for installation",
          "Tylok is used for high-pressure systems only"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Tylok uses an additional ferrule"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "With a sketch, show the difference between a single and a double flare.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Figure 13 - Single and double flares"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Figure 13 - Single and double flares"
      ],
      "explanation": "",
      "imageName": "Figure 13"
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "What angle of flare is utilized in the piping trade?",
      "type": "text_type",
      "options": [],
      "correctAnswer": ["45"],
      "explanation": "45°"
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "To make consistent bends on tubing, you should use _______ or _______.",
      "type": "checkbox_type",
      "options": [
        "Lever",
        "Mechanical benders",
        "Gear benders"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": [
        "Lever",
        "Mechanical benders",
        "Gear benders"
      ],
      "explanation": "Any of the following are acceptable: Lever; Mechanical benders; Gear benders"
    },
    {
      "id": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "topicId": "bd2b1c99-439a-4e6e-9f07-8ab25a7f4e9b",
      "question": "When bending larger sizes of tube, the better bender to use is the _______.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "manual type",
          "mechanical type",
          "hydraulic type",
          "electric type",
          "pneumatic type"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["mechanical type"],
      "explanation": ""
    }
  ]
}
